Guide to the Yale University Art Gallery Photographs and Film
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Art Gallery photographs and film
1925-1953
RU 622
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.25
The materials consist of photographs, drawings and one 16mm film documenting the two stages of construction of the Yale University Art Gallery (Gallery of Fine Arts).
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Custodial History
Accession 2012-A-075 transferred from Media Services, 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic and additional material.
Biographical / Historical
The Old Art Gallery (Old Wing) at Yale was completed in 1928. A bridge over High Street, connecting Street Hall to the Art Gallery, was constructed at the same time. The New Art Gallery (New Wing) adjoins the Old Wing on the west side. The New Wing was completed in 1953.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs, drawings and one 16mm film documenting the two stages of construction of the Yale University Art Gallery (Gallery of Fine Arts).
General
Formerly titled: Yale University Art Gallery Photographs. Title revised 3/29/2012.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Architectural records; Photographs; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Art Gallery; Yale University. Gallery of Fine Arts
- Photographs, Series I
  - Proposal drawings (prints of)
    - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Interior designs, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Construction (Old Gallery), 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 6)
  - Contruction (Addition)
    - Proposal, Circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1952 July, excavation (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1952 Sept-1953 March (Box 1, Folder 9 - 15)
  - Oversize, proposed addition, Circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Slides (Box 3)
  - Transparencies (Box 4)
  - Folio
    - Old Art Gallery, interior B sculpture gallery (Box DR24F79)
    - Art Gallery addition,Yale Daily News, 1953 (Box DR24F79)
- Film of Yale Art Gallery construction, Accession 2012-A-075
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research. Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Film of Yale Art Gallery Construction, Undated; 1 (Box 1)